<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Code Journal</title>
    <description>On June 29th, 2015, I embarked on a new adventure. I&#39;ve joined the 2nd-ever Chicago cohort of General Assembly&#39;s Web Development Intensive program.</description>
    <link>http://timrourke.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://timrourke.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 12:04:34 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 12:04:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Good outcomes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Much has been said about the promises of employment made by programming bootcamps over the past few years. A quick Google search for “programming bootcamp” turns up countless hits of posts and articles both critical and laudatory of the employment prospects of a bootcamp student. As a new student participating in this relatively untested educational model, I was naturally quite skeptical of strong claims about students beginning their careers with significant salaries and a bright future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to yesterday evening, and a chat with several students from the last cohort reveals more than a glimmer of hope. For a cohort of less than 20 students, more than 150 people responsible for hiring at Chicago tech firms were in attendance, meeting students and making offers. Several students came away with job offers after mere hours of conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing these kinds of experiences firsthand is far more powerful than the anecdotes I’ve read on the web. Sounds like I made a good choice of getting in on the gold rush.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 06:24:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timrourke.github.io/general-assembly/2015/07/02/good-outcomes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timrourke.github.io/general-assembly/2015/07/02/good-outcomes.html</guid>
        
        <category>General Assembly</category>
        
        <category>hiring</category>
        
        <category>outcomes</category>
        
        
        <category>general-assembly</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>General Assembly: A fresh start</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s happened. I finally pulled the trigger and made the leap. I’ve started my journey as a new student in the Web Development Immersive program at &lt;a href=&quot;http://generalassemb.ly/&quot;&gt;General Assembly in Chicago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officially GA’s second WDI cohort, our class is made up of students from many walks of life, all united by the desire to jump-start a new life in web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been dragging my feet about this for ages. While I’d been chewing on the idea of attending a development bootcamp for some time, I was outright terrified of the financial commitment required, not to mention the time I’d have to spend away from my &lt;a href=&quot;http://unsaidstud.io&quot;&gt;wonderful wife&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the incredible support and encouragement my family have shown over the last few months, the final burst of inspiration came in the form of a podcast. Back in April, one of my favorite programming podcasts, &lt;a href=&quot;http://devchat.tv/js-jabber&quot;&gt;Javascript Jabber&lt;/a&gt;, hosted the remarkable &lt;a href=&quot;http://aimeemarieknight.com/&quot;&gt;Aimee Knight&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://devchat.tv/js-jabber/153-jsj-careers-for-junior-developers-with-aimee-knight&quot;&gt;in an episode&lt;/a&gt; about her educational trajectory through web development, including her experiences before, during, and after her official training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t the specific details of her educational experience that changed my outlook on the process. It wasn’t the tech stack she learned, the money she made, or the street cred she built. And she spoke joyfully about all three of those things. What caught me off guard was her sense of personal satisfaction to have finally taken the leap into a rewarding new career in web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like me, Aimee started her life with a passion wholly different from her tech life. She entered her professional world as a figure skater, a practice that taught her discipline, tenacity, and self-expression. My own journey began with a deep study of classical drawing and painting. This pursuit would lead me all the way to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://florenceacademyofart.com&quot;&gt;Florence Academy of Art&lt;/a&gt;—it was a study that fed me, thrilled me, and enslaved my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until one day, it didn’t. Aimee talked about that too. She described the gut-wrenching sea change involved in doing a 180 in life. And she described the surprising comfort of embracing a set of technical tools that engaged the parts of her mind that were once lit with the uphill battle I can only imagine a serious career in figure skating must be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s my story!”, I thought. “I know this!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I begin my humble journey to something like proficiency in tools like Node.js, Rails, and Angular, I’m going to keep Aimee in my mind as a real life example of someone who took the bull by the horns and hammered out a world she’d never seen before with guts, code, a ton of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Aimee, for forging a path, and living to tell the tale.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 04:53:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timrourke.github.io/general-assembly/2015/07/01/a-fresh-start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timrourke.github.io/general-assembly/2015/07/01/a-fresh-start.html</guid>
        
        <category>General Assembly</category>
        
        <category>inspiration</category>
        
        <category>bootcamps</category>
        
        
        <category>general-assembly</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
